A Guide to the Office of the Messrs. Rockefeller records, Homes, Series I FA318
Rockefeller Archive Center
- Pocantico Hills, NY
  - Pocantico Hills - New House and Gardens - William Welles Bosworth - Tonetti's Group, 1909-1918 (Box 20, Folder 179)
    Girl and Fish, frogs, bouquet for fountain, children with flowers, bronze work in gardens. Dealt through Bosworth.
  - Pocantico Hills - New House and Gardens - William Welles Bosworth - Emil Siebern, 1918-1919 (Box 20, Folder 180)
    Sculpture work around Gardens.
  - Pocantico Hills - New House and Gardens - William Welles Bosworth - Villa Albani Vase, 1913-1918 (Box 20, Folder 181)
    Copy of Italian marble vase in porte cochere, $2,200.
  - Pocantico Hills - New House and Gardens - William Welles Bosworth - Winter Covers, 1914-1924 (Box 20, Folder 182)
    Construction and upkeep of covers for art works outside.
  - Pocantico Hills - New House and Gardens - William Welles Bosworth - Aphrodite Statue - Aphrodite Book, 1917-1932 (Box 20, Folder 183)
    Description of statue published by John D. Rockefeller, Jr.
  - Pocantico Hills - New House and Gardens - William Welles Bosworth - Aphrodite Statue - Appraisal and Acquisition, 1905-1959 (Box 20, Folder 184)
    Purchase, shipment from London, commission on sale, placing of statue in temple. Article on statue. Opinion by Metropolitan Museum experts that statue was made in 17th century. It had been purchased as a possible work of Praxiteles. Correspondents include John D. Rockefeller, Jr., William Welles Bosworth, J. J. Rorimer.
  - Pocantico Hills - New House and Gardens - William Welles Bosworth - Aphrodite Statue - Mr. DeKay, 1915-1917 (Box 20, Folder 185)
    Wrote first draft of Altoviti book. Paid $1,000.
  - Pocantico Hills - New House and Gardens - William Welles Bosworth - Aphrodite Statue - Distribution of Books, 1904-1953 (Box 20, Folder 186)
  - Pocantico Hills - New House and Gardens - William Welles Bosworth - Aphrodite Statue - Books and Studies, 1914-1917 (Box 20, Folder 187)
  - Pocantico Hills - New House and Gardens - William Welles Bosworth - Aphrodite Statue - Books and Studies - Strena Helbigiana, c. 1900 (Box 20, Folder 188)
  - Pocantico Hills - New House and Gardens - William Welles Bosworth - Barnard Statues - Hewer Statue, 1915-1925 (Box 20, Folder 189)
    Purchase for $25,000. Winter cover, copper screen.
  - Pocantico Hills - New House and Gardens - William Welles Bosworth - Barnard Statues - Primitive Woman, 1915-1928 (Box 21, Folder 190)
    Carving of statue, delays, Barnard's financial troubles. Smaller work of early sketches purchased by John D. Rockefeller, Jr. for $6,000. Large work, $25,000.
  - Pocantico Hills - New House and Gardens - William Welles Bosworth - Barnard Statues - The Prodigal Son, 1915-1923 (Box 21, Folder 191)
    At Pocantico on trial. John D. Rockefeller, Jr. decided against using it. Returned to Bosworth.
  - Pocantico Hills - New House and Gardens - William Welles Bosworth - Commissions, 1907-1924 (Box 21, Folder 192)
    Initial arrangements between John D. Rockefeller, Jr. and William Welles Bosworth. 100% overhead charge. Basis of Bosworth's charges for work done. Purchase made for Pocantico Hills on which commissions were paid to Bosworth. Includes porcelains. Adjustment of commissions. Details of construction expenses and alterations on house. Correspondents include John D. Rockefeller, Jr., William Welles Bosworth, Delano and Aldrich.
  - Pocantico Hills - New House and Gardens - William Welles Bosworth - Adjustment of Commissions, 1909-1911 (Box 21, Folder 193)
  - Pocantico Hills - New House and Gardens - William Welles Bosworth - Adjustment of Commissions, 1912-1913 (Box 21, Folder 194)
  - Pocantico Hills - New House and Gardens - William Welles Bosworth - Correspondence, 1942-1944 (Box 21, Folder 195)
    Garden at Kykuit. John D. Rockefeller, Jr. purchase of Sargent painting of John of Bologna, $1,000. Correspondents include John D. Rockefeller, Jr., William Welles Bosworth.
  - Pocantico Hills - New House and Gardens - F. F. Briggs, 1908-1947 (Box 21, Folder 196)
    Superintendent and Business Manager of estate. Staff problems. When Ellis became superintendent, Briggs remained business manager. Resigned at request of John D. Rockefeller in 1916. Kept Rockefellers informed of later life. Correspondents include John D. Rockefeller, John D. Rockefeller, Jr.
  - Pocantico Hills - New House and Gardens - F. F. Briggs - Tarrytown National Bank, 1915 (Box 21, Folder 197)
    John D. Rockefeller objects to large balances left in Tarrytown Bank by Briggs. Orders his account reduced to small amount with all transactions handled through New York office.
  - Pocantico Hills - New House and Gardens - Caldwell and Company, 1911-1924 (Box 21, Folder 198)
    Lighting contractors, inside and outside. Also made door handles, minor metal works. Additional fixtures. Correspondents include John D. Rockefeller, Jr.
  - Pocantico Hills - New House and Gardens - T. B. Clarke, 1909-1916 (Box 21, Folder 199)
  - Pocantico Hills - New House and Gardens - Ogden Codman, 1907-1913, 1984 (Box 22, Folder 200)
    Architect for interior of new house and for furnishing. Selection of items, commissions. Codman purchased ornaments for home in Paris. Correspondents include John D. Rockefeller, Jr.
  - Pocantico Hills - New House and Gardens - Ogden Codman - Fees and Commissions, 1906-1911 (Box 22, Folder 201)
    Payments, summary.
  - Pocantico Hills - New House and Gardens - Conservation of Wild Life and Swans, 1933-1961 (Box 22, Folder 202)
    Conservation Club of Tarrytown. Gift to Westchester County Game Preserve. Southern New York Fish and Game Association. Contribution request, annual donation. Correspondents include John D. Rockefeller, Jr.
  - Pocantico Hills - New House and Gardens - Conservation of Wild Life and Swans - Deer, 1959-1961 (Box 22, Folder 203)
  - Pocantico Hills - New House and Gardens - Cow Herd, 1924-1945 (Box 22, Folder 204)
    Attempt to develop a disease free herd. Successful in improving herd. Correspondents include John D. Rockefeller, John D. Rockefeller, Jr., John D. Rockefeller 3rd, E. P. Prentice.
  - Pocantico Hills - New House and Gardens - Delano and Aldrich, 1912-1913 (Box 22, Folder 205)
    Architects for new house. Objected to John D. Rockefeller, Jr.'s use of Ogden Codman for interior work. Purchase of some facilities for interior. Complaints about smoky chimneys.
  - Pocantico Hills - New House and Gardens - Delano and Aldrich - Charges and Commissions, 1902-1912 (Box 22, Folder 206)
    Payments to architects.
  - Pocantico Hills - New House and Gardens - Delano and Aldrich - Specifications for New House, 1906-1908 (Box 23, Folder 207)
  - Pocantico Hills - New House and Gardens - Dyson DeLap, 1919-1940 (Box 23, Folder 208)
    Estate superintendent. Maintenance correspondence. Use of buildings, gardening, expenses. Use of produce. Rental of buildings. Retirement. Correspondents include John D. Rockefeller, Jr., John D. Rockefeller 3rd, Dyson F. DeLap, B. Houston.
  - Pocantico Hills - New House and Gardens - Dogs, 1931-1957 (Box 23, Folder 209)
    Purchase. Correspondents include John D. Rockefeller, Jr., John D. Rockefeller 3rd, Robert W. Gumbel, E. Hignett.
  - Pocantico Hills - New House and Gardens - E. Dreyfus, 1909-1914 (Box 23, Folder 210)
    Purchase of garden furniture, small desk items. Correspondents include John D. Rockefeller, Jr.
  - Pocantico Hills - New House and Gardens - Duveen Brothers, 1908-1912 (Box 23, Folder 211)
    Purchase of furniture and pictures for house. Also Chinese vases. Correspondents include John D. Rockefeller, Jr.
  - Pocantico Hills - New House and Gardens - H. Ellis, 1913-1918 (Box 23, Folder 212)
    Hired as superintendent at Forest Hill. Brought to Pocantico. Did not work well with Briggs. Ellis handled outside maintenance. Managed wartime food gardens on estate. Correspondents include John D. Rockefeller, H. Ellis.
  - Pocantico Hills - New House and Gardens - Employees
    Wages, resignations, hiring, problems, health. Small gifts to employees during sickness. Death by gun shot of one employee. Deaths. Letters of appreciation. Aid to J. MacPhail, boy who shot his father. Correspondents include John D. Rockefeller, John D. Rockefeller, Jr., John D. Rockefeller 3rd, Dyson F. DeLap, Robert W. Gumbel.
    - Pocantico Hills - New House and Gardens - Employees, 1905-1935 (Box 23, Folder 213)
      Resticted from scholarly access - personnel material.
    - Pocantico Hills - New House and Gardens - Employees, 1936-1940 (Box 24, Folder 214)
    - Pocantico Hills - New House and Gardens - Employees, 1941-1946 (Box 24, Folder 215)
    - Pocantico Hills - New House and Gardens - Employees, 1947-1953 (Box 24, Folder 216)
    - Pocantico Hills - New House and Gardens - Employees, 1954-1957 (Box 24, Folder 217)
    - Pocantico Hills - New House and Gardens - Employees, 1958-1960 (Box 24, Folder 218)
  - Pocantico Hills - New House and Gardens - Employees
    Restricted from scholarly access - personnel material.
    - 1947 Bonus (Box 24, Folder 219)
      To L. Lewis, T. Cancannon, J. Oldham.
    - Edward Campbell, 1939-1943 (Box 25, Folder 220)
      John D. Rockefeller, Jr. monthly check. Death. Former tinsmith on estate.
    - Henry B. Fridy, 1943-1955 (Box 25, Folder 221)
      Engineer who worked for W. Kidde Constructors. Reports on progress. Payment of $100 a month. Philipse Castle, Old Dutch Church Cemetery, Pocantico Hills Restoration work. Correspondents include Henry B. Fridy.
    - William Johnson, 1937-1952 (Box 25, Folder 222)
      Chauffer. Illnesses, John D. Rockefeller, Jr.'s aid.
    - Robert Moore, 1929-1939 (Box 25, Folder 223)
      Employee, inactive. John D. Rockefeller concern. Monthly aid.
    - Medical Care, 1936-1941 (Box 25, Folder 224)
      Physical examinations.
    - Adolph Nelson, 1936-1948 (Box 25, Folder 225)
      Carpenter. Death. Aid to wife.
    - Arthur Roosa and Daniel E. Roosa, 1939-1956 (Box 25, Folder 226)
      Painters. Daniel Roosa's death. Arthur Roosa's illness. John D. Rockefeller, Jr.'s aid.
    - Mrs. Lotse Shwedo, 1926-1942 (Box 25, Folder 227)
      Carpenter's death. Widow. John D. Rockefeller, Jr.'s aid. Rent trouble.
    - Survey by Industrial Relation Counselors, Inc., 1936-1937 (Box 25, Folder 228)
      John D. Rockefeller, Jr.'s objection to survey.
    - Wages, 1919-1959 (Box 25, Folder 229)
      Constant pressure for higher wages for workmen. Overtime pay.
    - Edward Whalen, 1932-1946 (Box 25, Folder 230)
      John D. Rockefeller's butler at Pocantico Hills. Retirement.
    - George Wittlinger, 1918-1922 (Box 25, Folder 231)
    - John D. Rockefeller 3rd Correspondence, 1932-1937 (Box 25, Folder 232)
      Wages. Vacations. Rent on houses. Correspondents include John D. Rockefeller 3rd.
  - Pocantico Hills - New House and Gardens - Fire Apparatus - Inspection, 1913-1958 (Box 26, Folder 233)
    Purchase of fire engine. Fire district area. Correspondents include John D. Rockefeller, Jr., John D. Rockefeller 3rd.
  - Pocantico Hills - New House and Gardens - Furnishings, 1908-1923 (Box 26, Folder 234)
    Lists of furniture and furnishings in New House, 1908-1913. Not necessarily complete. Includes Garden expenses.
  - Pocantico Hills - New House and Gardens - Furnishings - Schmitt Brothers, 1908-1921 (Box 26, Folder 235)
    Purchase of andirons, canopied bed.
  - Pocantico Hills - New House and Gardens - Furnishings - Statements of Payment, Construction, 1908-1909 (Box 26, Folder 236)
  - Pocantico Hills - New House and Gardens - Furniture and Furnishings, 1937-1959 (Box 26, Folder 237)
    Selling and purchase of furniture. Chairs recaned by New York Institute for Education of Blind. Correspondents include John D. Rockefeller, Jr.
  - Pocantico Hills - New House and Gardens - Furniture and Furnishings - Arthur S. Vernay, Inc., 1939-1952 (Box 26, Folder 238)
    Furniture repair. John D. Rockefeller, Jr. gift to worker. Gift of Adam mantel to Albany Institute of History and Art.
  - Pocantico Hills - New House and Gardens - Garden, 1937-1957 (Box 26, Folder 239)
    Building trellis surrounding the Rose Garden. Correspondents include John D. Rockefeller, Jr., William Welles Bosworth.
  - Pocantico Hills - New House and Gardens - Garden - Garden Book Correspondence, 1917-1937 (Box 26, Folder 240)
    Manuscript for book. Arnold Genthes, William Welles Bosworth. Distribution of book.
  - Pocantico Hills - New House and Gardens - Gates, 1935-1957 (Box 26, Folder 241)
    Erecting Sister Gate. Correspondents include John D. Rockefeller, Jr.
  - Pocantico Hills - New House and Gardens - Gates - William Welles Bosworth, 1914-1916 (Box 26, Folder 242)
    Increase in height of main gates to satisfy John D. Rockefeller's desire for greater security.
  - Pocantico Hills - New House and Gardens - Gates - Delano and Aldrich, 1907 (Box 26, Folder 243)
    Costs of Gates.
  - Pocantico Hills - New House and Gardens - Gates - Thomas Dimond, 1904-1906 (Box 26, Folder 244)
    Gates for formal Gardens.
  - Pocantico Hills - New House and Gardens - Golf Course, 1934-1939 (Box 27, Folder 245)
    Search for golf course architect. Construction. Cost. Correspondents include John D. Rockefeller, Jr., John D. Rockefeller 3rd, Nelson A. Rockefeller, Webster Todd.
  - Pocantico Hills - New House and Gardens - Golf Course - Estimates, Specifications, Contract, 1935-1937 (Box 27, Folder 246)
    Golf course, Toomey and Flynn.
  - Pocantico Hills - New House and Gardens - Golf Course - Work on Lawns, 1937-1941 (Box 27, Folder 247)
    Contracting engineers, Toomey and Flynn.
  - Pocantico Hills - New House and Gardens - Heating and Lighting, 1903-1959 (Box 27, Folder 248)
    Purchase of boilers and fire boxes. Buying oil. Correspondents include John D. Rockefeller, Jr., J. Alva Jenkins.
  - Pocantico Hills - New House and Gardens - Heating and Lighting - 1952 Report on Boilers, 1952-1953 (Box 27, Folder 249)
    Report. New boilers installed.
  - Pocantico Hills - New House and Gardens - Heating and Lighting - Westchester Lighting Company, 1903-1926 (Box 27, Folder 250)
    Private electric power plant, purchase of additional power from Westchester Lighting Company, pole easement on Rockefeller lands, discussion of prices and rates.
  - Pocantico Hills - New House and Gardens - Heating Changes, 1942, 1942-1943 (Box 27, Folder 251)
    Converting from oil to coal.
  - Pocantico Hills - New House and Gardens - Heating Changes, 1942 - John D. Rockefeller, Jr. Letter to Children, 1942-1943 (Box 27, Folder 252)
    Concerning the oil heat in the winter.
  - Pocantico Hills - New House and Gardens - Housing, 1928-1955 (Box 27, Folder 253)
    Building Harman House at Pocantico. Housing problems with employees. Correspondents include John D. Rockefeller, Jr.
  - Pocantico Hills - New House and Gardens - Housing - Entrance and Office Building, 1931-1933 (Box 27, Folder 254)
    Contract for Office building. Iron gate agreement. Grosvenor Atterbury was architect. Correspondents include John D. Rockefeller, Jr.
  - Pocantico Hills - New House and Gardens - Housing - 1940 Prebuilt Housing, 1940-1941 (Box 27, Folder 255)
    Houses on Bedford Road. Heating problems. Correspondents include John D. Rockefeller, Jr., L. W. Lewis.
  - Pocantico Hills - New House and Gardens - Incorporation, 1935-1951 (Box 28, Folder 256)
    Tawhawus plan of incorporation. Development of Hills Realty Company, Inc. Transfer of John D.Rockefeller, Jr. property to realty company. Correspondents include Thomas M. Debevoise, Laurance S. Rockefeller.
  - Pocantico Hills - New House and Gardens - Incorporation - Incorporation Inventory, 1950 (Box 28, Folder 257)
    List of tangible personal property not included in transfer to new corporation. Correspondents include Phillip Keebler.
  - Pocantico Hills - New House and Gardens - House at Modern Museum, 1949-1950 (Box 28, Folder 258)
    House used as exhibit, relocated to Pocantico Hills, used by Nelson A. Rockefeller. Correspondents include John D. Rockefeller, Jr., Robert W. Gumbel.
  - Pocantico Hills - New House and Gardens - F. Keppel and Company, 1909-1927 (Box 28, Folder 259)
    List of prints purchased from company. Purchase of coaching prints 6,000 pounds, 1925. Purchase and cleaning of prints. Correspondents include John D. Rockefeller, Jr., H. V. Allison.
  - Pocantico Hills - New House and Gardens - L. W. Lewis Correspondence, 1926-1948 (Box 28, Folder 260)
    Authorization to make repairs. Correspondents include John D. Rockefeller, Jr., L. W. Lewis, John D. Rockefeller 3rd.
  - Pocantico Hills - New House and Gardens - Management, 1934-1940 (Box 28, Folder 261)
    Allocation of responsibility. John D. Rockefeller 3rd wants full responsibility of decisions on Estate. John D. Rockefeller 3rd discontinues management of Estate, 1939. Winthrop takes job. Correspondents include John D. Rockefeller, Jr., John D. Rockefeller 3rd.
  - Pocantico Hills - New House and Gardens - Management - Nelson A. Rockefeller Memos, October 1933 (Box 28, Folder 262)
    Organization Study.
  - Pocantico Hills - New House and Gardens - Miscellaneous, 1913-1930 (Box 28, Folder 263)
    Trouble with tenants and laborers. Accidents. Estate repair. Proposed incorporation of Pocantico. Proposed annexation to North Tarrytown. Use of bridle paths by neighbors. No publicity on mode of living of Rockefeller family policy. Scrap campaign, 1942. Request to photograph, rent house, use pasture land, etc. Threats from R. Gulich, lady who wants John D. Rockefeller, Jr. to take action against re-zoning. Correspondents include W. C. Briggs, John D. Rockefeller, Jr., Dyson F. DeLap, A. J. Bartlett, Robert W. Gumbel, Charles O. Heydt.
  - Pocantico Hills - New House and Gardens - Miscellaneous, 1913-1930 (Box 28, Folder 263A)
  - Pocantico Hills - New House and Gardens - Miscellaneous, 1931-1940 (Box 29, Folder 264)
  - Pocantico Hills - New House and Gardens - Miscellaneous, 1941-1961 (Box 29, Folder 265)
  - Pocantico Hills - New House and Gardens - Miscellaneous - Adams Antique Furniture, 1908-1911 (Box 29, Folder 266)
    Purchase of antique furniture for Kykuit.
  - Pocantico Hills - New House and Gardens - Miscellaneous - John A. Bank, 1914-1919 (Box 29, Folder 267)
    Made stand for porcelains, John D. Rockefeller bust.
  - Pocantico Hills - New House and Gardens - Miscellaneous - Mrs. Lillian Bowles, 1919-1952 (Box 29, Folder 268)
  - Pocantico Hills - New House and Gardens - Miscellaneous - F. L. Byrd, 1933-1952 (Box 29, Folder 269)
    Accountant at Pocantico for 10 years. Resigned.
  - Pocantico Hills - New House and Gardens - Miscellaneous - Charles, Dealer in Antique and Decorative Works of Art, 1907-1924 (Box 29, Folder 270)
    Purchase of furniture and some prints.
  - Pocantico Hills - New House and Gardens - Miscellaneous - A. J. Crawford, 1906-1908 (Box 29, Folder 271)
    Purchase of furniture.
  - Pocantico Hills - New House and Gardens - Miscellaneous - Employment, 1926, 1930-1931 (Box 29, Folder 272)
    John D. Rockefeller, Jr. hires Tarrytown men on road work as relief measure.
  - Pocantico Hills - New House and Gardens - Miscellaneous - Fairchild Aerial Survey, 1940-1941 (Box 29, Folder 273)
    Air views of Estate. John D. Rockefeller 3rd's interest.
  - Pocantico Hills - New House and Gardens - Miscellaneous - Fire, November 1925, 1925-1929 (Box 29, Folder 274)
    Began in paint shop. Destroyed apartment above, 18 year old girl died.
  - Pocantico Hills - New House and Gardens - Miscellaneous - Eugene Glaenzer and Company, 1908 (Box 29, Folder 275)
    Antique and Decorative Works of Art. Bought two statues, gate, Veronian well curb. $6,580.
  - Pocantico Hills - New House and Gardens - Miscellaneous - E. Gottschalk, 1908 (Box 29, Folder 276)
    Purchase engraving, A. Hamilton - $200.
  - Pocantico Hills - New House and Gardens - Miscellaneous - Hardware, 1907-1910 (Box 29, Folder 277)
    Purchase of hardware.
  - Pocantico Hills - New House and Gardens - Miscellaneous - Albert Herter, 1907-1912 (Box 29, Folder 278)
    Purchase of tiles, rugs, curtains for house.
  - Pocantico Hills - New House and Gardens - Miscellaneous - William H. Jackson and Company, 1906-1914 (Box 30, Folder 279)
    Tile work on house. Iron work outside.
  - Pocantico Hills - New House and Gardens - Miscellaneous - E. A. Knoedler, 1907-1911 (Box 30, Folder 280)
    Purchase of engraving prints.
  - Pocantico Hills - New House and Gardens - Miscellaneous - Koopman and Company, 1906-1911 (Box 30, Folder 281)
    Purchase of antique furniture.
  - Pocantico Hills - New House and Gardens - Miscellaneous - Kykuit Park, 1958-1961 (Box 30, Folder 282)
  - Pocantico Hills - New House and Gardens - Miscellaneous - Laundry Cottage, 1940-1957 (Box 30, Folder 283)
    Margaret Johnson was laundress. John D. Rockefeller, Jr. gift.
  - Pocantico Hills - New House and Gardens - Miscellaneous - Mauterstock Property Boundary, 1925-1926 (Box 30, Folder 284)
    Compromise on short stretch of line.
    Opened per DHS, February 16, 2001.
  - Pocantico Hills - New House and Gardens - Miscellaneous - New Superintendent, 1940-1941 (Box 30, Folder 285)
    Application for position. Mr. Bartlett for position.
  - Pocantico Hills - New House and Gardens - Miscellaneous - James P. Silo, 1908-1914 (Box 30, Folder 286)
    Purchase of Japanese print, etc. at auction. Lanterns for garden.
  - Pocantico Hills - New House and Gardens - Miscellaneous - Melville E. Stone, 1908-1925 (Box 30, Folder 287)
    Article on house for House Beautiful magazine.
  - Pocantico Hills - New House and Gardens - Miscellaneous - Tarrytown History, 1920-1925 (Box 30, Folder 288)
    Celebration of fifty years of incorporation - North Tarrytown.
  - Pocantico Hills - New House and Gardens - Miscellaneous - Transmission Lines Through County, 1931-1933 (Box 30, Folder 289)
    Action to prevent high tension wires in Sawmill River Valley.
  - Pocantico Hills - New House and Gardens - Miscellaneous - Underground Wires, 1932-1933 (Box 30, Folder 290)
    John D. Rockefeller, Jr.'s authorization.
  - Pocantico Hills - New House and Gardens - Miscellaneous - Vaughn-Eames, 1935-1952 (Box 30, Folder 291)
    Care of trees on Estate.
  - Pocantico Hills - New House and Gardens - Miscellaneous - War Precautions, 1941-1942 (Box 30, Folder 292)
    Buckets, pumps, shatter proof glass.
  - Pocantico Hills - New House and Gardens - Miscellaneous - Watershed, 1921 (Box 30, Folder 293)
    Proposed use of Rockefeller land by Tarrytown for watershed protection - no action here.
  - Pocantico Hills - New House and Gardens - Miscellaneous - Wells and Newton, 1906-1910 (Box 30, Folder 294)
    Installed and repaired plumbing at Kykuit.
  - Pocantico Hills - New House and Gardens - Miscellaneous - Westchester Airport, 1934-1941 (Box 30, Folder 295)
    Objection to location in Valhalla. Site changed to Rye Lake.
  - Pocantico Hills - New House and Gardens - Miscellaneous - Westchester County History, 1923-1926 (Box 30, Folder 296)
    Proposed work, chapter on Kykuit.
  - Pocantico Hills - New House and Gardens - Miscellaneous - Zoning Committee, 1926-1931 (Box 30, Folder 297)
    Changing in zoning in Pocantico area.
  - Pocantico Hills - New House and Gardens - Oceanus Fountain, 1913-1922 (Box 30, Folder 298)
    Moving base stone through Tarrytown. Statue a copy of one in Italy. Copied by Bosworth from photographs. Case of fountain. Settling. Correspondents include John D. Rockefeller, Jr.
  - Pocantico Hills - New House and Gardens - Orangerie, 1908-1913 (Box 31, Folder 299)
    Bids on building, construction, revisions, repairs in 1913. Correspondents include John D. Rockefeller, Jr., William Welles Bosworth.
  - Pocantico Hills - New House and Gardens - Frederick Law Olmsted, 1928-1939 (Box 31, Folder 300)